Thomas Wood Stevens papers, 1895-1984 (bulk 1897-1937)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series V: Pageants, 1900-1941
  The folders within the boxes of these various pageants are not detailed in this inventory. They may, or may not, contain typescripts, published versions, programs, photographs, clippings, correspondence, notes, etc. The amount and type of material for each pageant will vary. Unless otherwise indicated, pageants are authored by Thomas Wood Stevens.
  - Pageant of the Italian Renaissance, Art Institute of Chicago. 1909 (Box 30)
  - Pageant of Illinois, Evanston, Illinois. 1909 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Pageant of Ireland, Chicago, Illinois. 1910 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Pageant of the Old Northwest, Milwaukee, Wisconsin. 1911 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Pageant for Independence Day, Jackson Park, Chicago, Illinois. 1911 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Pageant of Madison County, Edwardsville, Illinois. 1912 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Masque of Montezuma, Indiana Sand Dunes. 1912 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Shakespeare Pageant, Lincoln Park, Chicago, Illinois. 1912 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Wisconsin Pageant, University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wisconsin. 1913 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Demeter and Persephone, First Ravina Harvest Festival, Illinois. 1913 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Pageant of St. Clair County, Belleville, Illinois. 1914 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    See Box 42 for clippings.
  - Pageant and Masque of St. Louis, St. Louis, Missouri. 1914 (Box 32, Folder 4-6)
    See Box 42 for clippings, Box 4 for correspondence with Percey Mackaye, Box 5 for correspondence with Donald Robertson and Joseph L. Smith.
  - Masque of the Nations, Wilmerding, Pennsylvania. 1915 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Technology Pageant and the Masque of Power, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, Massachusetts. 1916 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Duquesne Pageant and Masque, Duquesne, Pennsylvania. 1916 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Duquesne Christmas Mystery, Duquesne, Pennsylvania. 1916 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Pageant of Newark, Newark, New Jersey. 1916 (Box 33, Folder 5-7)
    See Box 42 for clippings
  - Indiana Dunes Pageant. 1917 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Pageant of Florida, Tallahassee, Florida. 1917 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - (Box 33)
  - The Drawing of the Sword (Red Cross Pageant). 1917 (Box 34)
    Also version produced as Fighting for Freedom, St. Louis, 1918
  - Joan of Arc, Carnegie Institute of Technology, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. 1918 (Box 35)
    Later produced in France.
  - Louisiana Pageant, New Orleans, Louisiana. 1918 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - East Liberty Presbyterian Congregation, 100 Years Ago: The Meeting, East Liberty, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. 1919 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Hidden Treasures of the Earth, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. 1919 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    In celebration of the dedication of the Pittsburgh Station, Bureau of Mines, Department of the Interior.
  - Pageant of Victory and Peace, with the threnody for those who fell, Carnegie Institute of Technology, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. 1919 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - America, historical pageant for the Winona Assembly, Winona Lake, Indiana. 1920 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Civic Pageant, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. 1920 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Missouri 100 Year Ago, St. Louis, Missouri. 1921 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Pageant of Virginia, Richmond, Virginia. 1922 (Box 36, Folder 8-10)
  - Adventure, written for the 12th annual Safety Congress of the national Safety Council, Buffalo, New York. 1923 (Box 37, Folder 1-3)
  - Pageant of Ypsilanti, Michigan. 1923 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Pageant of Kaukauna, Wisconsin. 1923 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Rensselear Polytechnic Institute Pageant, Troy, New York. 1924 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Pageant of Jacksonville, Jacksonville, Illinois. 1923 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Pageant of Charlotte and Old Mecklenburg, Charlotte, North Carolina. 1925 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Santa Fe Fiesta, Santa Fe, New Mexico. 1927 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Magna Carta, written for the American Bar Association, Seattle, Washington. 1928 (Box 38, Folder 4-5)
  - George Rogers Clark Pageant, Vincennes, Indiana. 1929 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Ohio in Education, written for the National Education Association, Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio. 1930 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Yorktown Pageant, Yorktown, Virginia. 1931 (Box 39, Folder 2-5)
  - Beethoven's Ninth Symphony, Madison Square Garden, New York City. 1933 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Boston Tea Party, St. Louis, Missouri. 1933 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Old Fort Niagara, Niagara Falls, New York. 1934 (Box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - O, Sing a New Song, Chicago, Illinois. 1934 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - De Soto Pageant, Florida. 1938 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Pageant for the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. 1941 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    Never produced.
  - The Entrada of Coronado, Albuquerque, New Mexico. 1940 (Box 41)
  - Oversize clippings: Pageant of St. Clair County. 1914 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    See Box 32.
  - Oversize clippings: Pageant and Masque of St. Louis. 1914 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Oversize clippings: Technology Pageant. 1916 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    See Box 33.
  - Oversize clippings: Pageant of Newark. 1916 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Oversize clippings: Drawing of the Sword. 1917 (Box 42, Folder 5)
    See Box 34.
  - Oversize clippings: Missouri 100 Years Ago. 1921 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    See Box 36.
  - Oversize clippings: Pageant of Virginia. 1922 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Oversize clippings: Pageant of Charlotte and Old Mecklenburg. 1925 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    See Box 38.
  - Oversize clippings: Yorktown Pageant. 1931 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    See Box 39.
  - Oversize clippings: Old Fort Niagara. 1934 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    See Box 40.
  - Oversize clippings: Entrada of Coronado. 1940 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    See Box 41.
  - Pageant correspondence: miscellaneous. 1910-1921 (Box 43, Folder 1-11)
  - Pageant correspondence: American Pageant Association. 1913-1919 (Box 43, Folder 12)
    Frank C. Brown and others.
  - Pageant correspondence: miscellaneous. 1922-1941 (Box 44, Folder 1-6)
  - Pageants Authored by Others, 1908-1932
    - Alexander, B. H., The Mystery of Life. 1913 (Box 45)
      A poetization of "The Hako," a Pawnee ceremony.
    - Andrews, Charlton, The Interrupted Revels. 1910 (Box 45)
      A masque, first performed at the Hotel Plaza, New York City, December 20, 1910. Autographed by the author.
    - Applin, Arthur, Torquay (England) Historical Pageant. 1924 (Box 45)
      A portrayal of Devon's glorious history, folklore and romance. Includes a note to Thomas Wood Stevens from Lucy Barton in front.
    - Baird, George, Pageant and Masque of Freedom. 1916 (Box 45)
      Pittsburgh Charter Centennial Committee prompt book.
    - Baker, George Pierce, The Centenary Pageant of Allegheny College, 1815-1915. 1915 (Box 45)
      Performed June 21, 22, and 24, 1915. Accompanied by the Official Pageant Program.
    - Bates, Esther W., A Pageant of the League of Free Nations. 1919 (Box 45)
    - Bates, William O., The Indianapolis Centennial Pageant. 1920 (Box 45)
      Coliseum, June 8, 1920. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by the author.
    - Conwell, O'Kane, The Caldwell Pageant. 1915 (Box 45)
      In celebration of the 225th anniversary of the settlement of Caldwell, New Jersey, Independence Day, 1915.
    - Cowley, Frederick K., Wenonah, or, The Magic Word. 1916 (Box 45)
      Produced by the Tennessee Coal, Iron and Railroad, Company on the occasion of the changing of the name of Fossil, Alabama to Wenonah, Alabama, November 1916.
    - Cram, Ralph Adams, Excalibur. 1909 (Box 45)
      An Arthurian drama. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by the author.
    - Dickey, Jeston and Roselle, B. L. D., Pageants and Plays of Pioneers. 1935 (Box 45)
      Commemorating the centennial of Texas.
    - Erskine, John, A Pageant of the Thirteenth Century for the Seven Hundredth Anniversary of Robert Bacon. 1914 (Box 45)
      Given by Columbia University. 750 copies were printed and 500 offered for sale. This copy is number 161, signed by the author.
    - Gaither, Frances, Shores of Happiness. 1919 (Box 45)
      A pageant whereof Odysseus is hero.
    - Gaither, Frances, The Shadow of the Builder. 1921 (Box 45)
      The centennial pageant of the University of Virginia as presented June 1, 1921.
    - Geddes, Patrick, The Masque of Ancient Learning. 1913 (Box 45)
    - Geddes, Patrick, The Masque of Medieval and Modern Learning. 1913 (Box 45)
    - Hayden, Willard, Pageant of Lexington. 1915 (Box 45)
      Commemorating a century of peace between United States and England and in aid of the American Red Cross.
    - Howard, Sidney, Lexington. 1925 (Box 45)
      Second presentation of the historical pageant drama, commemorating the 150th anniversary of the Battle of Lexington, enacted every ten years by the citizens of Lexington, Massachusetts. June 1925.
    - Johnson, D. B., (Master of the Pageant), Old English Pageant. 1913 (Box 45)
      The visit of Queen Elizabeth to Kenilworth Castle. Presented by the students of Winthrop College, South Carolina, May 13, 1913.
    - Keller, Martha & others, The Kenilworth Revels. 1924 (Box 45)
      Vassar College.
    - Koch, Frederick H., Raleigh, The Shepherd of the Ocean. 1920 (Box 45)
      A pageant-drama designed to commemorate the tercentenary of the execution of Sir Walter Raleigh. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by the author.
    - Langdon, William C., The Bronxville Christmas Mystery. 1914 (Box 45)
      Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by the author.
    - Langdon, William C., Suggestions for the Celebration of the Fourth of the July by Means of Pageantry. 1912 (Box 45)
    - Langdon, William C., The Centennial Pageant of Auburn Theological Seminary, 1818-1918. 1918 (Box 45)
    - Langdon, William C., The Chapel Masque of Christmas. 1913 (Box 45)
    - Langdon, William C., Foundation Day Ceremonial for Indiana University. 1920 (Box 45)
    - Langdon, William C., The Pageant of Darien. 1913 (Box 45)
      The pageant of a residential community, inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by the author.
    - Langdon, William C., The Pageant of Indiana. 1916 (Box 45)
      In Riverside Park on the banks of the White River, Indianapolis, October 2-7, 1916. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by the author.
    - Langdon, William C., The Pageant of St. Johnsbury. 1912 (Box 45)
      In celebration of the 125th anniversary of the founding of the town of St. Johnsbury, Vermont. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by the author.
    - Leonard, Martia, The Masque of Manhattan. 1909 (Box 45)
    - Long, George, Pageant of the Church. 1916 (Box 45)
      In honor of the general convention of the Protestant Episcopal Church.
    - Mackay, Constance D'Arcy, Patriotic Plays and Pageants for Young People. Holt & Company. 1912 (Box 46)
    - Mackaye, Percy, Caliban by the Yellow Sands. Doubleday, Page & Company. 1916 (Box 46)
      A community masque to commemorate the tercentenary of the death of Shakespeare.
    - Mackaye, Percy, The Roll Call. 1918 (Box 46)
      A masque of the Red Cross.
    - Mackaye, Percy, Wakefield. 1932 (Box 46)
      A folk-masque of America, being midwinter night's dream of the birth of Washington. Designed and written for the United States Commission for the celebration of the 200th anniversary of the birth of George Washington.
    - Mackaye, Percy, The Evergreen Tree. D. Appleton & Company. 1917 (Box 46)
      A masque of Christmas time for community singing and acting. Accompanied by a guide.
    - Nichols, Adelaide, At the Gate of Stars. 1918 (Box 46)
      A patriotic masque.
    - North Dakota University, Sock and Buskin Society, A Pageant of the North-west. 1914 (Box 46)
      Written in collaboration by eighteen undergraduate members of the Sock and Buskin Society under the direction of Professor Frederick H. Koch. First presented at the 7th annual meeting of the Mississippi Valley Historical Association and on the occasion of the dedication of the Bankside Theatre on the campus of the University of North Dakota. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by Professor Koch.
    - New Trier Township High School, Illinois, How the Pilgrim Spirit Came to Illinois. 1921 (Box 46)
      A pageant written and presented by the students and faculty in commemoration of the tercentenary of the landing of the Pilgrims.
    - Pomona College, Claremont, California, Historical Pageant. 1913 (Box 46)
      Given by Pomona College and the city of Claremont, California in honor of the 25th anniversary of the founding of Pomona College.
    - Parker, Louis N., The Dover Pageant. 1908 (Box 46)
      Dover, England.
    - Parker, Louis N., The Warwick Pageant. 1906 (Box 46)
      In celebration of the 1000th anniversary of the conquest of Mercia by Queen Ethelfleda, Warwick, England.
    - Pashley, Hattie S. & Dunn, Eleanor R., Pageant of Palos. 1916 (Box 46)
      Presented by the people of Palos Township, Illinois.
    - Potter, Marie W., The Winged Soul. 1925 (Box 46)
      A festival for the 50th anniversary of the founding of Wellesley College. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by E. R. Stoner.
    - Rice, Wallace & Goodman, Kenneth Sawyer, The Glorious Gateway of the West. 1916 (Box 46)
      An historic pageant of the story of Fort Wayne, commemorating the 100th anniversary of Indiana's admission to the sisterhood of states. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by Wallace Rice.
    - Rice, Wallace, Illinois Centennial Plays, numbers 1-3, 5. 1918 (Box 46)
      no. 1 - Children of the Illini (about 1673)
      no. 2 - Children of France (about 1778)
      no. 3 - Pioneer Boys and Girls (1814)
      no. 5 - Children of the Civil War (February 1862)
    - Rice, Wallace, The Masque of Illinois. 1918 (Box 46)
      Intended for the use of high schools, colleges and communities during the centennial year. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by the author, notes, etc. laid in.
    - Rice, Wallace, The Pageant of the Illinois Country. 1918? (Box 46)
      Intended for use throughout the state in county and local celebrations.
    - Rice, Wallace, Primavera; the masque of Santa Barbara. 1920 (Box 46)
    - Rockwell, Ethel T., The Apostles of Light. 1923 (Box 46)
      A religious pageant-drama of the Centenary Movement. Also: Appendix. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by the author.
    - Saint Paul Institute, School of Art, Pageant of Minnesota History. 1911 (Box 46)
    - Scott, Aggie Dean, The Early Settlement of Georgia as Told in Historical Playlets. 1932 (Box 46)
    - Seward, Edith de Charms and Latham, Azubah J., The Masque of Joy or Drudgery Transformed. 1914 (Box 46)
      Acting version used at the New Year Festival, Teachers College, Columbia University, New York, January 10, 1914.
    - Stocking, Helen. Historical Community Pageant of San Jose. 1917 (Box 46)
      Luna Park, San Jose, California, June 1-2, 1917.
    - Tanner, Virginia, A Pageant of Portsmouth. 1923 (Box 46)
      A pageant in celebration of the tercentenary of the first settlement in New Hampshire. Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by the author.
    - Tanner, Virginia, A Pageant to the State of Maine. 1928 (Box 46)
      In celebration of the official dedication of the Carlton Bridge, Bath Maine.
    - Van Orden, Mary, Partheneia and The Queen's Masque. 1915 (Box 46)
      The Queen's Masque is the fourth Partheneia of the University of California, Berkeley, California.
    - Viehman, Theodore A., and Smith, Howard F., The Pageant of Tuscaloosa. 1916 (Box 46)
      Presented May 30, 1916, as a feature of the Tuscaloosa Centennial Celebration, held in commemoration of the 100th anniversary of the arrival of the first white settlers on the site of Tuscaloosa. Signed by the authors.
    - Williams, Francis Howard, Philadelphia Historical Pageant. 1912 (Box 46)
      Inscribed to Thomas Wood Stevens by Edith Emerson.
    - Wisconsin University, A Pageant of the University. 1914 (Box 46)
      Given on the campus July 29, 1914. Written and directed by the class in pageantry.
    - Yale University, The Book of the Yale Pageant. Yale University Press. 1916 (Box 46)
      In commemoration of the 200th anniversary of the removal of Yale College to New Haven. Edited by George Henry Nettleton. Letter to Thomas W. Stevens regarding the Pageant laid in, signed "Kay" on letterhead paper of William O. Goodman.
  - Miscellaneous Pageant Material, 1900-1930
    - American Pageant Association Bulletin. 1914-1919 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Cranbrook Masque, Bloomfield Hills, Michigan. 1916 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous pageant programs. 1900-1930 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous pageant material. (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Pilgrimage and Passion Plays; programs (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Architectural Review. September 1916 (Box 47)
      "Some Garden Theatres," by Frank A. Waugh, pp. 161-167.
    - Country Life in America. November 1916 (Box 47)
      "The Pageant in America," by Frances G. Wood, pp. 21-25.
    - Dickinson, Thomas H., "The Pageant; a study of its history structure, and social uses." The Play Book, Wisconsin Dramatic Society, vol. 2, no. 4. 1914 (Box 47)
    - Davol, Ralph A., A Handbook of American Pageantry. Davol Publishing Company. 1914 (Box 47)
    - Hurley, George O., "Pageantry for Ohio Communities." State Historical Society of Iowa, Bulletin of Information Series, no. 10. 1923 (Box 47)
    - Lewis, B. Roland, "Pageantry and the Pilgrim Tercentenary Celebration (1620-1920)." Bulletin of the University of Iowa, vol. 10, no. 4, University of Utah Press. 1920 (Box 47)
    - Mackaye, Percy, The New Citizenship: a civic ritual devised for places of public meeting in America. Macmillan. 1915 (Box 47)
    - National Pageant Association, The National Historical Pageants. Historical productions adapted tot he purpose of historical societies, universities and various civic organizations. Books by Thomas Wood Stevens. Chicago. (2 copies). 1910 (Box 47)
    - Russell Sage Foundation, Department of Child Hygiene, Independence Day Celebrations. New York. 1925 (Box 47)
    - Withington, Robert, "Manual of Pageantry." Indiana University Bulletin, vol. 13, no. 7, Indiana University Extension Division. June 15, 1915 (Box 47)
- Series VI: Published Works and Manuscripts, 1896-1984
  - Little Magazines, Typographia, Stagecraft, 1896-1910
    - The Bachelor Book, Chicago, Illinois, vol. 1, no. 1, 3-5,, vol. 2, no. 2. March, May-July, November 1900 (Box 48, Folder 1)
      Contains contributions by Thomas Wood Stevens.
    - Bradley, His Book, Springfield, Massachusetts, vol. 1, no. 2 & 3. June, July 1896 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - The Bibelot, Portland, Maine, vol. 16, no. 1. January 1910 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - The Westminster Chapbook, Franklin, Indiana, book 1, no. 1. June 1902 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Stiletto, Chicago, Illinois, vol. 1, no. 2 & 4. (September, November 1900) (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Louis McPherson, editor of The Pebble and Thomas Wood Stevens. ca. 1900 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Goudy and the Village Press: miscellaneous material. (Box 48, Folder 4)
      See Box 3 for correspondence.
    - Typographia: miscellaneous material. (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Pyle, Howard: letter to Forrest Crissey. No Date (Box 48, Folder 6)
      Copy made by Thomas Wood Stevens. Contains autobiographical information.
    - Stagecraft: miscellaneous material. (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - The Pebble, Omaha, Nebraska, vol. 1. 1900 (Box 48)
      Contains a poem by Thomas Wood Stevens, p. 186.
    - The Philosopher, Wausau, Wisconsin, vol. 6, vol. 7. July-December 1899 & January-June 1900 (Box 48)
      Contains stories and poems by Thomas Wood Stevens and articles regarding the Blue Sky Press.
  - Blue Sky Press, 1899-1928
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood and Noble, Alden Charles, Technologie Ballads. 1899 (Box 49)
      Number 12 of 99 copies printed, signed by Stevens.
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood, In the Sack of the Castle, Blue Sky Booklets, vol. 1, no. 1. 1900 (Box 49)
      (3 copies), 93 copies printed, signed by Stevens.
    - Kinmarck, Michael, The End of Malcom Brewster, Gentleman, a colonial tale, Blue Sky Booklets, vol. 1, no. 2. 1900 (Box 49)
      (2 copies), 97 copies printed, signed "Michael Kinmarck," pseudonym of Thomas Wood Stevens.
    - McIlvaine, Mabel, Changing Skies, Blue Sky Booklets, vol. 1, no. 3. 1900 (Box 49)
      (3 copies) 95 copies printed, signed by the author.
    - Egbert, Marion Thornton, In Old Madras, Blue Sky Booklets, vol. 1, no. 4. 1900 (Box 49)
      Number 27 of 145 copies printed. Signed by the author.
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood, The Unsought Shrine. 1900 (Box 49)
      (2 copies) 50 copies printed.
    - Fowler, Egbert Willard, The Storm, Blue Sky Booklets, vol. 1, no. 5. 1900 (Box 49)
      Numbers 15 and 77 of 123 copies printed. Signed by the author.
    - Allen, Frank Allen, My Ships Aground, Blue Sky Booklets, vol. 1, no. 6. 1900 (Box 49)
      Number 52 of 125 copies printed. Signed by the author.
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood, The Frown of Victory, Blue Sky Booklets, vol. 2, no. 1. 1900 (Box 49)
      A song-story. Numbers 40 (unsigned), 97 (signed) and one unnumbered, unsigned copy of 195 copies printed.
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood and Noble, Alden Charles, Mucronis Puerique. 1900 (Box 49)
      Two papers of a casual nature, "The Dagger in the Book," by Thomas Wood Stevens and "The Boy in the Book," by Alden Charles Noble. Number 45 of 98 copies printed, signed by A. G. Langworthy.
    - Moore, Edward Martin, Spoil of the North Wind. 1901 (Box 49)
      Numbers 30 and 179 of 625 copies printed.
    - Noble, Alden Charles, Scott, Who was Nine. 1901 (Box 49)
      A tale of the joyous universe. Number 23 of 200 copies printed on Ruisdael hand-made paper and number 6 of 15 copies on Imperial Japan vellum.
    - Becker, Charlotte, The Glass of Time. 1901 (Box 49)
      Number 133 of 250 copies on Ruisdael hand-made paper, number 8 of 15 copies on Imperial Japan vellum.
    - Peattie, Elia W., How Jaques came into the Forest of Arden. 1901 (Box 49)
      Numbers 120 and 543 of 700 copies on Van Gelder hand-made paper, number 15 of 25 copies on Japan vellum and three copies on parchment.
    - Blanden, Charles Granger, Omar Resung. 1901 (Box 49)
      Number 25 of 25 copies printed in Japan vellum, 200 additional copies printed on Van Gelder hand-made paper.
    - Crissey, Forrest, In Thompson's Woods. 1901 (Box 49)
      Number 17 of 25 copies on Japan vellum, 275 additional copies on L. L. Brown's hand-made paper.
    - Stevens, Thomas Wood, Our Lady of Rhyme. 1901 (Box 49)
      A book of occasional lyrics. (2 copies) 200 copies printed.
    - The Blue Sky. 1899-1902 (Box 49)
      vol. 1, no. 1-5, August-December, 1899
      vol. 2, no. 1-5, January-June, 1900 (2 copies of no. 1)
      vol. 3, no. 1-5, July 1900-June 1901 (2 copies of no. 2, 3, 5)
      vol. 4, no. 1-5, November 1901-March 1902 (2 copies of no. 1, 2)
      vol. 4, no. 1, April 1902
    - The Rubric: A Magazine de Luxe. 1902 (Box 49)
      This magazine absorbed The Blue Sky in 1902.
      vol. 1, no. 2, January 1902
      vol. 2, no. 1, August 1902
    - The Blue Sky Booklets. 1900 (Box 49)
      vol. 1, no. 1-6
    - Blue Sky Press: miscellaneous material. (Box 49)
      Includes catalogs, advertising material, etc., and a letter from Will Ranson (January 10, 1928) regarding a list of Blue Sky publications for this forthcoming book on private presses.
    - Rice, Wallace, Memorial Ode for the Fiftieth Anniversary of the Founding of Racine College, Racine Wisconsin, X Junii MCMII. 1902 (Box 50)
    - Noble, Alden Charles, Lyrics to the Queen. 1902 (Box 50)
      Contains " A 'Stray Cloud,' being a final word to the friends of the Blue Sky magazine," by Thomas Wood Stevens. (2 copies).
    - Browning, Robert, In a Balcony. 1902 (Box 50)
      Number 215 of 400 copies on paper, 15 additional copies of Japan vellum.
    - Milton, John, L'Allegro & Il Penseroso. 1902 (Box 50)